Kennerley mss., 1928-1976 LMC 1571
Lilly Library
Kennerley mss.
1928-1976
Lilly Library
Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957
Dunn, Thomas A.
Kennerley, Mitchell, 1878-1950
Kennerley, Morley, -1985
Morley, F. V. (Frank Vigor), 1899-1980
Morley, Lilian Janet Bird, approximately 1866-1939
Westgate, Lewis G. (Lewis Gardner), 1868-1948
LMC 1571
1 Box 1 standard
The Kennerley mss., 1928-1976, consists primarily of letters and essays of author Christopher Darlington Morley, 1890-1957, sent to editor Morley Kennerley, 1902-1985.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Acquisition Information
Purchase: 1985-1986
Gift: 1986,1992
Biographical Note
Christopher Darlington Morley, 1890-1957, was a poet, novelist, playwright, and lecturer. He was born on May 5, 1890 in Bryn Mawr, Pennsylvania, the son of Frank Morley and Lilian Janet Bird. After graduating from Haverford College in 1910, Morley went on to study modern history at Oxford University. He began his literary career by working as a publicist and publisher's reader at Doubleday. Morley's first novel, Parnassus on Wheels, was published in 1917, and several others soon followed, including The Haunted Bookshop (1919). He authored several books of essays and volumes of poetry, and he served as one of the founders and editors of the Saturday Review of Literature. Morley's fascination with Sir Arthur Conan Doyle's Sherlock Holmes series led him to help found the Baker Street Irregulars in 1902, a society dedicated to all things related to Sherlock Holmes. He died on March 28, 1957.
Morley Kennerley, 1902-1985, was a publisher and editor. He was born on October 19, 1902 in New York City, the son of publisher Mitchell Kennerley and his wife Helen. He graduated from Yale in 1925 and followed in his father's footsteps by entering the publishing business. He joined the board of British publisher Faber and Faber in the 1930s and worked there until his retirement from the firm in 1965. Kennerley also acted as Christopher Morley's editor for many of his published works. He married Jean Simpson-Baikie in 1932, and they had a daughter, Jean Barbara Diana Kennerley. After the death of Mitchell Kennerley in 1950, he worked to preserve his father's legacy. He contributed to the biography The Fortunes of Mitchell Kennerley, Bookman(1986), but did not live to see its publication, as he died on February 28, 1985.
Scope and Content Note
The Kennerley mss., 1928-1976, consists primarily of letters and essays of author Christopher Darlington Morley, 1890-1957, sent to editor Morley Kennerley, 1902-1985. Most of the letters were written on Saturday Review of Literature letterhead.
Other correspondents present are Thomas Allen Dunn, Frank Vigor Morley, Lilian Janet (Bird) Morley, and Lewis Gardner Westgate. A few of the postcards are addressed to Kennerley's father Mitchell Kennerley.
There is a list of the essays in the Vertical File. Also present in the collection is a file of bibliographic descriptions relating to publications by Christopher Morley, and an undated photograph of him.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series: I. Correspondence; II. Writings; III. Miscellaneous Materials.
Publishers and publishing; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957
- I. CORRESPONDENCE
  Scope and Contents
  Content in this series is arranged chronologically.
  - 1928-1930
  - 1931
  - 1932-1948
  - 1949-1970
  - 1971-1976
- II. WRITINGS
  Content in this series is arranged alphabetically.
  - A-E
  - F
  - G-Q
  - R-S
  - T-V
  - W-Z
- III. MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS
  - Bibliographic descriptions for Christopher Morley publications
  - Photographs
  - Printed